<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Hong's Blog</title><link href="https://pagpires.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pagpires.github.io/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pagpires.github.io/</id><updated>2017-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>2017 New Year Resolution</title><link href="https://pagpires.github.io/2017-new-year-resolution.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><author><name>Xinyu Hong</name></author><id>tag:pagpires.github.io,2017-01-17:2017-new-year-resolution.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;2016 has passed. It is a year that means a lot to me. I failed two projects in my research and had a very hard time; I made a breakthrough with my proviously-considered-dead-ended project. Most importantly, I made up my mind to pursue another career path and started somewhat systematic training. I touched database system, front-end programming, interactive data vizualization, deep learning and now I feel I'm ready to make something. Here are my 2017 resolutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep learning courses&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://cs231n.github.io/"&gt;Stanford's cs231n&lt;/a&gt; (Computer Vision, focus on CNN)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://cs224d.stanford.edu/syllabus.html"&gt;Stanford's cs224d&lt;/a&gt; (Natural language processing, focus on RNN)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www0.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/d.silver/web/Teaching.html"&gt;UCL's Reinforment Learning&lt;/a&gt; (by DeepMind's David Silver)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://edge.edx.org/courses/course-v1:BerkeleyX+CS188x-SP16+SP16/info"&gt;UCBerkeley's cs188&lt;/a&gt; (General AI course)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://courses.cs.washington.edu/courses/cse512/16sp/"&gt;UW's CSE512&lt;/a&gt; (Data vizualization by D3 creator Jeffry Heer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects/Applications&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CNN: video face detection. Video in, friends' info out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RNN: haven't decided yet, need to spend some time on cs224d and see if there's anything interesting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RL: "Sheng-ji" bot player&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Viz (to be determined)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S.
After one year of exposure to data science, I find it actually has a lot in common with my work: biological research: 1) both requires you to spend a lot of time to find out the right way to address the right question; 2) techniques are important, but most of the labs/companys use well-defined techniques and the harder part is to rationalize your choice of technique; 3) (therefore,) both requires you to be a good communicator and 4) (many times) you will need different ways (aspects) to make the same argument.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="New Year Resolution"></category></entry><entry><title>Styling of the blog using theme 'elegant' with modifications</title><link href="https://pagpires.github.io/styling-of-the-blog-using-theme-elegant-with-modifications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><author><name>Xinyu Hong</name></author><id>tag:pagpires.github.io,2016-09-11:styling-of-the-blog-using-theme-elegant-with-modifications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was looking for a pelican theme that was simple and elegant enough so that both readers and I can focus more on the blog content. The pelican theme &lt;a href="http://oncrashreboot.com/elegant-best-pelican-theme-features"&gt;'elegant'&lt;/a&gt; partially satisfied my needs but I was not quite happy with the font.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until I saw Edward Tufte published the &lt;a href="https://edwardtufte.github.io/tufte-css/"&gt;'Tufte CSS'&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across those famous ET's books when I was a 2nd-year grad student. My PI always emphasized to us the importance of effective scientific communication. Therefore unsurprisingly we had all kinds of ET's books on data visualization as well as some others' work on scientific writing. I read his books and started to know a research field/discipline called data visualization and became more and more interested in it. Also, I really liked the styling in his books, the simplicity, the carefully chosen typography and the famous 'no more than 3 levels of headings'. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore I changed some of the font-family in 'elegant' to those 'tufte fonts'. You basically go to your blog and inspect-element on the writings with those fonts you don't like, and then search for these fonts in base.html file in your theme folder and replace them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tweaks to set up 'elegant' theme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plugins&lt;br /&gt;
This theme support a search bar, which requires plugin &lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-plugins/tree/master/tipue_search"&gt;'tipue_search'&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-plugins/tree/master/sitemap"&gt;'sitemap'&lt;/a&gt;. You need to download &lt;code&gt;tipue_search&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sitemap&lt;/code&gt; plugins and specify them in your pelican configuration file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Template pages&lt;br /&gt;
By default this theme creates additional static pages like &lt;code&gt;404.html&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;search.html&lt;/code&gt;. You need to specify them by adding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;TEMPLATE_PAGES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;themePATH/elegant/templates/404.html&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;404.html&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;themePATH/elegant/templates/search.html&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;search.html&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;into your configuation file.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links 'undefined'&lt;br /&gt;
If you see all the search results are associated with 'undefined' links, check this &lt;a href="https://github.com/talha131/pelican-elegant/issues/147"&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; . The easiest hack is to edit tipue_search.py and add &lt;code&gt;'loc': page_url&lt;/code&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;node =&lt;/code&gt; dicts in both &lt;code&gt;def create_tpage_node&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;def create_json_node&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="practice"></category></entry><entry><title>It's just a curve</title><link href="https://pagpires.github.io/its-just-a-curve.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><author><name>Xinyu Hong</name></author><id>tag:pagpires.github.io,2016-08-12:its-just-a-curve.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After trying different tools for my blogging system, I eventually settled with &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;pelican&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;github page&lt;/strong&gt;. Here are my reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Markdown&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need a system to write easily. WordPress and Markdown are my choices however Markdown has a better geeky flavor. More importantly, I will integrate the interactive data visualization into the webpage. WordPress can do this with some plugins however it doesn't support JSON to be upload, therefore I would have to upload my data source in my server while uploading the CSS and JS script to WordPress, which is annoying. After I saw this &lt;a href="http://www.nicksuch.com/2014/03/26/d3-sample/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, it became very natural that Markdown is &lt;em&gt;the choice&lt;/em&gt; to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Pelican&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing Markdown for blogging I will need a tool to generate static web pages. Since I plan to write some data analysis reports and to record my progress in &lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/"&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; every once a while, I will often use ipython notebook and integrate it into my blog. Then &lt;a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/3.6.3/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, a python-based tool for generating static web pages, seems to serve that role, especially after I saw this &lt;a href="https://www.dataquest.io/blog/how-to-setup-a-data-science-blog/"&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; for setting up a data science blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;GitHub&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing GitHub is just to add some more geeky flavor to this blog. This might also force me to be familiar with project version control, which is an essential skill to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically that's how I ended up with these three gadgets for my blogging system. Either in terms of proficiency of these three tools, or in terms of skillfulness in the data science field that I'm going to cover in this blog, I'm both a newbie. However, for a systematically trained scientist-to-be like me, nothing can be hard after some dedicated time and efforts. It's just a learning curve, isn't it?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="thoughts"></category></entry></feed>